JOEL VENZKE

1126 25th St \diamond Apt 6 \diamond Des Moines, IA 50311 $(507) \cdot 261 \cdot 8311 \diamond ioel.venzke@drake.edu$

JoelVenzke.com \(\phi \) github.com/Joel-Venzke \(\phi \) linkedin.com/in/JoelVenzke

SUMMARY

One and a half years of research experience in computational science

Experience using supercomputing technologies such as Stampede (TACC) and Gordan (SDSC)

Experience in data and numerical analysis

Presented research at local, regional, and national conferences

Quick to learn new skills, techniques, and algorithms

EDUCATION

Drake University

B.S. in Computer Science, Mathematics, and Physics

Society of Physics Students Chapter President

Math Club Vice President

Physics Tutor

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Computational Atomic Physics, Ultrafast Electronic Dynamics

Undergraduate Researcher

PI: Klaus Bartschat, Ph.D.

August 2014 - Present Drake University

Cumulative GPA: 3.85

August 2012 - May 2016 (expected)

- · Simulated ultrafast laser pulse interactions on the hydrogen atom
- · Used Fortran and OpenMP to parallelize wave-function propagation
- · Interfaced with XSEDE Supercomputers such as Stampede (TACC) and Gordan (SDSC)
- · Preformed numeric testing and data analysis

Computational Bioinfromatics, Automating NRM Assignment

 $Undergraduate\ Researcher$ PI: Timothy Urness, Ph.D. September 2013 - Present Drake University

- · Automated the assignment of error prone nontrivial NMR datasets
- · Implemented Artificial Intelligence based algorithms in Python
- · Interfaced with machine learning software
- · Worked with Unit testing software

American Mathematical Society (AMS), Sage Math

 $Undergraduate\ Researcher$

PI: Jason Grout, Ph.D.

September 2013 - May 2014 Drake University

- · Developed open source math software
- · Trained new developers on code base
- · Developed pythreejs, a Python/three.js bridge for web-based graphics

Signal and Image Analysis, MCTP Pre-REU

 $Undergraduate\ Researcher$ PI: Gregory Berkolaiko, Ph.D.

June 2013 - July 2013 Texas A&M University

- \cdot Developed fraud protection software
- · Implemented signature analysis algorithms in MatLab
- · Applied Fourier Analysis and Wavelet Decomposition to analyze signatures
- · Tested algorithms performance against a signature database

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Times-Delphic

Photo Editor/Staff Photographer

September 2012 - Present Des Moines, IA

- · Trained and managed staff photographers
- · Produced quality work within strict deadlines
- · Photographed major events and stories

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages Python, C/C++, Java, Fortran, Bash Scripting

Parallel Computing CUDA, OpenMP

Software Skills Vim, Sublime Text, Git, Gnuplot, LATEX, Command Line, ssh/sftp

Operating Systems Mac OSX, Linux, Windows 7

Specialties Parallel Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Data Analysis

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS AND PUBLICATIONS

Presentations

· Joel Venzke. "Pulse-Shape Effects on the Autler-Townes Doublet in Strong-Field Ionization of Atomic Hydrogen". Tuscan, AZ, October 2014. Frontiers In Optics: 98th OSA/APS Annual Meeting (FiO 2014). Poster

- · Joel Venzke. "Automated Assignment Of Backbone NMR Data with A*". Verona, Wisconsin, April 2013. Midwest Instruction and Computing Symposium (MICS). Talk
- · Joel Venzke "Automated Assignment Of Backbone NMR Data with A*". Des Moines, Iowa, April 2013. Drake University Conference on Undergraduate Research in the Sciences (DUCERS). Talk
- · Joel Venzke "Signature Authentication Using Wavelets and Fourier Analysis". College Station, Texas, July 2013. Mentoring through Critical Transition Points Symposium (MCTP). Talk

Conference Publications

· Joel Venzke. "Automated Assignment Of Backbone NMR Data with A*". Verona, Wisconsin, April 2013. Midwest Instruction and Computing Symposium (MICS).

HONORS/AWARDS

Drake University Presidents List	Spring 2014
Drake University Top Sophomore	Spring 2014

Drake University Deans List Fall 2012 - Fall 2013

Drake Physics Prize Scholarship, Full TuitionSpring 2012Drake University Presidential ScholarshipSpring 2012Boy Scouts of America Eagle Scout AwardSpring 2012